aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Brutal aliens escaped from the Space Prison Sargasso.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들
To protect the Earth from those evil hands, Brave Dagwon fights on to this day.
그 마수로부터 지구를 지키기 위해 오늘도 계속해서 싸우는 용자 다그온
Now, a new member has been dispatched from the Space Police Organization; his name is Thunder Rai.
그들에게 지금 우주 경찰 기구에서 파견된 새로운 멤버, 선더 라이가 가담했다
In the deepest of the sea, a plane was brightening.
바다 밑바닥에서… 비행기가 빛나고 있었어…
White Wings of Resurrection
부활의 하얀 날개
Space Asura Shura
Appears
우주의 아수라 슈라
등장
Do- don't come, you- what the-?!
오, 오지마!
이녀석… 아니?!
Do- don't come!
오, 오지마!
Go away, you demon!
저리가, 이 똥개 녀석…
Good dog.
착하지
Good dog, calm down.
착하지, 화 풀으렴
Don't do that! You're going to get bitten!
그, 그만둬
그러다 물린다구!
Huh?
어레?
I guess you did something bad?
뭔가 잘못이라도 한 거죠?
No, nothing special...
아니, 난 그다지…
I'm sorry! I ran over his tail with my bicycle!
내가 잘못했어!
자전거로 꼬리 밟았어!
Sorry, but please forgive him.
미안해, 용서해 주렴
Well then, bye-bye.
그럼, 안녕
What's wrong?
왜 그래?
Do you feel sick?
어디 아프니?
I'm alright.
괘, 괜찮아요
If you're too tired, I'll get you home.
무리하지마
집까지 바래다 줄게
Sankai General Hospital
산카이 종합병원
Minako, are you hospitalized here?
미나코, 너 여기에 입원해 있는 거야?
-Yeah.
-Don't overdo it.
-응
-너무 무리하지마
But tomorrow's my brother's birthday!
그치만, 내일은 오빠 생일인 걸
I was going to get a present.
선물 사러 가는 길이었어
I see.
그렇구만
I hoped I could get an awesome present and make him happy.
뭔가 멋진 책을 선물해서 기쁘게 해 주려고 했는데…
I guess you like your brother?
오빠를 좋아하는구나
Yeah! I really like him!
응! 정말정말 정~말 좋아!
I understand! Don't feel down.
알았어, 꿍해 있지 말라구
I'll buy one for you tomorrow!
내가 내일 대신 사다줄 테니까
-Really?
-Yeah!
-정말?
-그래
Just you wait.
마음 놓고 기다리고 있어 응!
Brother!
앗, 오빠
Where did you go to, Minako?
어디 다녀왔니, 미나코?
A short walk.
잠깐 산책하고 왔어
Don't overdo it.
너무 무리하지마
Yeah!
응
Oh, right.
아, 맞다
Look at this.
이거 봐
In the deepest of the sea, a plane was brightening.
바다 밑바닥에서 말이야
커다란 비행기가 반짝반짝 빛나고 있었어
The deepest of the sea?
바다 밑바닥?
Isn't it weird? It wasn't a submarine.
이상하지?
잠수함이 아니었어
But, Minako's dream is already right...
하지만, 미나코의 꿈은 꼭 들어맞으니까…
I wonder what it is.
대체 뭘까?
For this reason, for Minako's brother, we must pick an excellent book!
이러한 이유로
미나코의 오빠를 위해… 멋진 책을 골라야만 한단 말씀!
I want to refer to you gentlemen's opinions.
제군들의 의견도 참고하고 싶어
You're going to call us gentlemen now?
제군들의 의견 좋아하시네!
You just don't know what book to pick because you always end up goofing off reading comics!
평소에 만화만 읽고 히죽대니까 어떤 책을 골라야할지 모르는 것 뿐이잖냐!
But isn't he being nice?
그래도 기특하잖아
Let's think about it.
모두 함께 생각해 보자
You're right! Alright!
그 말대로입니다 좋았어!
Why don't we think about it together?
모두 함께 생각해 보자구!
Hey, Shin! Any ideas?
이봐, 신!
뭔가 알고 있겠지?
Indeed.
그렇구만
Every male will like certain kinds of books!
역시 남자가 좋아할 만한 책이라면…
Ouch!
으흐하하하하하하~ 아얏!
What are you thinking, you pervert?!
무슨 생각 하는 거야, 저질!
You idiot, you should feel bad!
바보녀석, 반성해라!
Next, Kai! Your suggestion?
다음, 카이
넌 어때?
How about a Japanese literature collection?
일본 문학 전집 같은 건 어떨까?
That's too expensive!
그건 비싸서 무리야
Then how's this?
그럼 이걸 추천해 드리지요
A reptile picture book!
파충류 도감!
That's too maniac!
너무 오타쿠적이잖아!
Put it away! Put it away!
탈락, 탈락!
How about mysterious things?
괴기물 같은 건 어떨까?
Maybe about UFOs or monsters?
UFO라든가 요괴라든가…
Oh, that would be great!
오호옷, 그게 좋겠구만!
Hey, just a moment!
아앗, 잠깐 기다려 주세요
We should listen to Ryu senpai, too.
류 선배의 의견도 들어봐야지요
Hmph, what does Ryu know about books?
흥, 류가 책에 대해 뭘 알겠어?
How about an Anthology of Wordsworth?
워즈워스의 시집 같은 건 어때?
Wor... who's that?
워… 그게 뭐냐?
Wordsworth.
워즈워스
He's a poet of Wordsworth who often wrote about mysterious exchanges between humankind and nature.
영국의 시인으로 자연과 인간의 신비적인 교류를 노래한 낭만적인 도서야
Sankai General Hospital
산카이 종합병원
Minako Hashiba
하시바 미나코
Ah, brother!
아, 오빠
You look like you're having fun.
무척 즐거워 보이는구나
Let me introduce him.
응, 소개할게
이쪽은…
It's Senjuu.
센쥬입니다
I am Minako's doctor for today.
오늘부터 미나코 양의 주임이 되었습니다
I see. I'm indebted.
그렇습니까
잘 부탁드립니다
I'm going to be with you for a long time.
너와는 오랫동안 함께할 테니까 말이지
Minako!
미나코!
Huh? What's wrong, brother?
응?
왜 그래, 오빠?
You... you...
너, 너…
What's up? You're weird, brother.
뭐야, 오빠도 참…
Only you can see them.
너에게만 보인다
These arms.
이 팔은 말이지…
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
It's your turn.
이번엔 선생님 차례예요
-Hurry!
-Ah, sorry.
-어서요
-아아, 미안 미안
I won't lose this time!
이번엔 지지 않을 거예요
We'll see about that. I'll win again!
이런 이런
또 이겨 드리지요 미나코 양
I have never lost in this game.
전 이 게임에서 져본 적이 없거든요
Now!
지금이다!
Give up with your futile struggle.
부질없는 발버둥은 관둬라
You cannot win in this match.
이 승부에서 네게 승산은 없어
What's your objective?!
목적이 뭐냐?!
Well, it is simple.
뭐, 간단한 거야
I'd like you to kill a person.
사람을 한 명 죽여줬으면 해
En Daidouji.
다이도우지 엔을 말이야
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
Yo- you bastard!
이, 이자식…!
Do it. You will do it.
죽여라, 죽이란 말이다
It's not like you can decide.
네게 선택의 여지는 없어
Oh, right, brother.
아, 맞다
오빠
Look at this.
저기, 이것 좀 봐
From last night's dream...
오늘 꾼 꿈…
There's a book in the chest part of the red cloth.
빨간 옷의 가슴 부분에 책이 있어
What could it be?
대체 뭘까?
Minako.
미나코
I suddenly remembered something I have to do.
오빠가 잠시 볼일이 생각났어
Hurry and come back soon!
금방 돌아와야 해 그래…
I'll be playing with Minako.
미나코 양의 놀이 상대는 제가 맡겠습니다
Don't worry and take your time.
마음 놓고 다녀오세요
Brother, we have contact from Hido!
형, 히도에게서 연락이 왔어
Seems that he's doing pretty well!
일은 잘 진행되고 있다는군
The key of Dagwon is Power Dagwon.
다그온의 중심은 파워 다그온
That guy is most troublesome.
녀석이 가장 까다롭지
If we defeat Power Dagwon, we can do anything with the others.
파워 다그온만 해치운다면 나머지는 어떻게든 요리할 수 있다
That's our smart brother!
역시 형은 머리가 좋아
If we kill a Dagwon before it transforms and fights, it'll be like twisting a baby's arm.
녀석과 직접 싸우지 않고 변신 전의 다그온을 죽이면 갓난아기 손을 비트는 것과 다름없지
Moreover, a comrade of Dagwon will do it.
게다가 해치우는 건 동료니까 말이야
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Huh?
어레?
Ryu senpai! I wasn't expecting you here!
류 선배
우연이네요
Would you like ride?
같이 타고 가지 않으실래요?
Hey, senpai!
아앗, 선배!
Please wait for me!
기다려 주세요
Hido!
히도!
I hope you're not hesitating.
설마, 망설이는 건 아니겠지?
Shouldn't you do as your Doctor Senjuu ordered?
센쥬 선생님의 명령대로 하지 않으면 안될텐데?
Ryu senapi! Try Dag-
류 선배!
트라이 다그오…
Don't do it!
그만둬!
Leave your hands out of this!
상관하지…
상관하지 마라!
N-no way...
그, 그럴수가…
How unsightly, huh? Ryu?
꼴사납구만~
응~? 류
You bastard!
이자식!
Why are you stopping me?!
어째서 막는 겁니까?!
Why can't I fight?!
어째서 싸워선 안되는 겁니까?!
Maybe you can talk about why.
한 번 말해 보시지
Of course you wouldn't.
말할 수 있을 리가 없지
You'll have to do so anyway.
할 수밖에 없어 넌 말이야!
What's going on?
어떻게 된 겁니까?
What the heck is this about?
대체 무슨 일입니까?!
It has nothing to do with you.
너와는 관계없는 일이야
N- no way!
그, 그럴수가!
Ryu senpai!
류 선배!
Wordsworth... Words...
워즈워스… 워즈…
Oh, here it is!
어… 이, 있다!
I hope En comes as soon as possible.
엔, 빨리 와 줬으면 좋겠는데…
En?
엔?
He's my friend.
친구예요
I asked him for a present for my brother.
오빠의 생일선물을 부탁했어요
I hope he comes before my brother comes back.
오빠가 돌아오기 전에 와 주었으면 좋겠는데…
Oh, I see.
그래, 그렇구나
Will he ever come again?
과연 올 수나 있을까?
What's up, Ryu?
왜 그래, 류?
En, did you buy the present?
엔, 선물은 샀어?
Yeah, I bought it. What about it?
응, 샀는데
그건 왜 물어?
En...
엔…
I'm sorry, but you must die!
미안하지만, 죽어줘야겠다!
Minako!
미나코!
Welcome back, brother!
어서와, 오빠
I was looking through the window.
창문으로 보고 있었습니다
I am a traitor now.
난 이제 배신자다
That's right.
그 말대로다
You betrayed and killed your comrade to save your sister.
너는 동생을 구하기 위해 동료를 배신하고 죽였다
You won't be able to go back to your comrades ever again!
더 이상 동료들에게 돌아갈 순 없어
It's stuck as expected.
역시 꽂혀 있어
That Ryu punk...
류 녀석…
En Daidouji.
다이도우지 엔
Brave Seijin!
브레이브 성인!
Look.
보거라
Fire Jumbo!
파이어 점보!
What's going on?!
어떻게 된 거야?!
Sargasso is now well-organized because of the Three Warugaia Brothers, and they're hard to deal with.
와르가이아 3형제에 의해 조직화된 사르갓소는 생각 이상으로 상대하기 벅차다
You will most certainly need Fire Dagwon in the final battle.
최후 결전에 반드시 파이어 다그온이 필요해질 것이다
Did you revive it because of that?
그것 때문에 부활시켜 준 거야?
You are correct.
그렇다
But this is as much as the Space Police Organization can do.
하지만 우주 경찰 기구가 할 수 있는 것은 여기까지다
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이지?
The future of your planet will be worth it only when you earthlings protect your planet yourselves.
자신들의 별의 미래는 자신들이 지켜내야 가치가 있지 않겠는가
Go! Your comrade is in danger.
가라! 동료가 위험에 처해 있다
Alright!
좋았어!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Fire En!
파이어 엔
Who will you deal with next?
다음은 누구를 처리할까?
I'd choose Kai.
나라면 카이를 노릴 거다
Kai is like a tactician to Dagwon.
카이는 다그온에게 있어 군사와 같은 존재다
If we're to kill him, the faster, the better.
해치우려면 빠를수록 좋아
But still, a human is truly foolish, to suggest to kill your comrade yourself.
하지만, 네 쪽에서 먼저 동료를 해치우겠다고 하다니 정말 인간이란 생물은 어리석기 그지없구나
Yo- you bastard!
이, 이자식!
-Minako!
-B-brother!
-미나코…!
-오빠!
How impudent!
건방진 녀석!
I'm not letting you get away!
놓치지 않는다!
I'll send you siblings to the hell together!
남매끼리 사이좋게 지옥에 보내주마!
Die!
죽어라!
Long time no see, this feeling!
오랫만이군, 이 감촉!
Are you alright, Minako?
괜찮아, 미나코?
Yeah.
응…
En senpai?!
엔 선배?
What the hell is going on?!
대체 어떻게 된 겁니까?!
What?!
아니?!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Darkness is coming, crisis is approaching Earth
어둠이 온다 지구에 위기가 다가온다
You will rise
그대여 일어나라
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Transform to Fire En
파이어 엔으로 변신이다
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체
(火炎合體)
Go toward the figure of an enemy recklessly
무조건 적을 향하는 그 모습
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
like the light on a fuse
도화선의 불길처럼
Damn Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온 녀석!
Track down to anywhere
어디까지나 밀어붙이는 거야
It's the best!
최고야!
I never thought I could fight as Fire Dagwon once again!
설마 다시 한 번 파이어 다그온으로 싸울 수 있게 될 줄이야!
A formidable opponent in the fighting spirit
강적에 투지를 불태워
I'll act as violently as I want!
마음껏 날뛰어주마!
Go increase your power
파워를 올려 상대해라
How's that?!
어떠냐?!
Somebody, help me!
누가 좀 도와줘요!
What?!
아니?!
Fight! Shatter! Their ambitions!
쳐라! 때려부셔라! 녀석들의 야망
Why you-!
이자식!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Make them regret coming to Earth
지구에 온 것을 후회하게 만들어 주어라
Leave this to us!
이쪽은 맡겨둬라!
Alright, I'm counting on you!
좋았어, 부탁한다!
Run! Strike! With the overflowing youth
달려라! 쳐라! 넘쳐흐르는 젊음과
Jet Fire Storm!
제트 파이어 스톰!
Go with the strength of flame, dear invincible fighter
불꽃의 힘을 품은 무적의 파이터
Fire Hold!
파이어 홀드
Fire Blade!
파이어 블레이드
Finish!
피니시!
That's our Fire Dagwon!
역시 파이어 다그온
Strong!
강하다!
Your brother is...
오빠는 말이지…
...saved, thanks to Minako's dream.
미나코의 꿈 덕분에 살았어
Really?
정말?
Yeah.
그래
Hey, Ryu!
여봐, 류!
Look what you've done!
이거 어떻게 할 거야?!
This book was for Minako!
이 책은 말이야 모처럼 미나코을 위해서…!
I didn't know you two knew each other!
두사람은 서로 아는 사이였구나
I'm sorry, Minako.
미안해, 미나코
What should we do with this ripped book...
부탁받은 책이 이지경이 돼서…
-I'll take it.
-Brother.
-받을게
-오빠
What the, brother?! Could it be...
에엑, 오빠?! 설마…
Minako's brother... is Ryu?!
미나코의 오빠가… 류?!
This is the best present ever.
이런 멋진 선물은 처음이군
Thank you, En.
고맙다, 엔
Uh... that is... um...
아니, 그게… 뭐야…
I never knew that you had a sister...
네게 동생이 있다니
난 지금까지 전혀…
Uh, what's going on? I don't get it at all.
저기, 뭐가 어떻게 된 건가요? 전 도무지 모르겠습니다
I never thought Ryu had such a cute sister!
류에게 저런 귀여운 여동생이 있을 줄이야… 그러게요
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
What?! Ark Seijin appeared again?!
뭐야, 아크 성인이 나타났다고?!
It's been some time! I can't wait to fight!
꽤 오랜만이군
이거 좀이 쑤시는걸
No! We fell into his trap! Help us!
우리, 녀석의 함정에 빠져 버렸어! 꺼내줘!
I see that its target this time is me!
이번의 녀석의 표적은 바로 나인가!
I'll face you, Ark Seijin!
받아주마, 아크 성인!
Hey, Lian! Don't hurry up! Wait for us!
이봐, 라이안!
서두르지 말라구! 우리가 갈 때까지 기다려!
I can't! This is the last battle between him and me!
그럴 순 없어! 이건 나와 녀석과의 최후의 대결이야!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Howl! Lian
다음회 용자지령 다그온
외쳐라! 라이안
I'm going to have revenge for the 2 billion people of Sword Planet right now!
검성 20억 백성의 원수
지금이야말로 갚아주마!
Howl! Lian
외쳐라! 라이안